<?xml version="1.0"?>

<application>


  <descr>
    <name>Thick-thin sepraration</name>
    <author>Qgar Project, LORIA</author>
    <copyright>2004 - Qgar Project, LORIA</copyright>
  </descr>


  <documentation>
    <doc>
      <brief>
Separate thick line segments (or components) from thin line segments
(or components) in a binary image, using operators of Mathematical Morphology.
      </brief>
      <long>
<![CDATA[
<p>
The result is obtained by consecutively performing an
8-connexity-based opening (i.e. a composition of an
erosion and a dilation) and a geodesic recontruction,
using a square structural element.
The size (i.e. width) of the structural element should be an
odd number. If it is not the case, the size is automatically
rounded to the nearest superior odd number.
</p>
<p>
Line segments are then classified according to their thickness
(width). Line segments having a width greater than the structural
element size are stored in a given file, and line segments having
a width smaller or equal to the structural element size are
stored in second, separate given file.
</p>
<p>
In fact, the method does not only apply to line segments: The source
image may contain any kind of graphical elements, identified as
the black connected components. Let <i>c</i> be such a component.
The (connected) parts of <i>c</i> which fit the structural element
(i.e. in which the structural element can be moved without overrunning
the border) are considered as ''thick'' elements, the other parts are
considered as ''thin'' elements.
</p>
<p>
<b>Warning:</b> Let <i>s</i> be the size of the structural
element. Because of the very nature of Mathematical Morphology
operations, the content of the <i>s</i> rows and columns
contiguous to the borders of the resulting image is not
relevant.
</p>
]]>
      </long>
    </doc>
  </documentation>


  <paramlist>
    <param name="Source Image" flag="in" required="true" passing-mode="in"
           type="binary" format="PBM">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file containing the source binary image.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file must be one of the binary formats described
by the PBM+ specification (either raw or ASCII).
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="image of thick lines" flag="outhick" required="true" passing-mode="out"
	   type="binary" format="PBM" default="_.thick.pbm">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file to store the thick line segments.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="image of thin lines" flag="outhin" required="true" passing-mode="out"
           type="binary" format="PBM" default="_.thin.pbm">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file to store the thin line segments.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="Thin line max width" flag="size" required="true" passing-mode="out"
           type="numeric" format="int" default="6" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Maximum size (i.e. width) of a thin line segment.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
Line segments whose width is greater than the given value are classified as
''thick'', the others are classified as ''thin''.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


  </paramlist>


</application>
