<?xml version="1.0"?>

<application>

 
  <descr>
    <name>Prune Small Connected Components</name>
    <author>Qgar Project, LORIA</author>
    <copyright>2004 - Qgar Project, LORIA</copyright>
  </descr>


  <documentation>
    <doc>
      <brief>
Prune small black connected components of a given binary image.
      </brief>
      <long>
<![CDATA[
<p>A (connected) component is a region defined by a set of connected
pixels having the same color.</p>

<p>Only black components are considered here.
The application delivers two binary images, one containing the black components
of the given image having a size smaller than a given threshold, the other
containing the black components having a size greater than the threshold.</p>

<p>This application is faster than the construction of the whole set of
components of the image (see class qgar::ConnectedComponents in the QgaLib
library), as it does not construct any effective component: Small components are
detected by simply examining configurations of 2*3 pixels (based on 8-connexity)
in consecutive pairs of rows of the given image.<p>
]]>
      </long>
    </doc>
  </documentation>


  <paramlist>
    <param name="source image" flag="in" required="true" passing-mode="in"
    type="binary" format="PBM">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file containing the source binary image.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file must be one of the binary formats described
by the PBM+ specification (either raw or ASCII).
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="image of small CC" flag="outscc" required="true" passing-mode="out"
	   type="binary" format="PBM" default="_.smallCC.pbm">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
<![CDATA[
Full pathname of the file in which the <i>small</i> components will be
stored, i.e. components with a  size smaller or equal to the maximum introduced
by flag <tt>-size</tt>.
]]>
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="image of big CC" flag="outbcc" required="true" passing-mode="out"
	   type="binary" format="PBM" default="_.bigCC.pbm">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
<![CDATA[
Full pathname of the file in which the <i>big</i> components will be stored,
i.e. components with a size greater than the maximum introduced by flag
<tt>-size</tt>.
]]>
	  </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="small CC max size" flag="prune" required="true" passing-mode="in"
	   type="numeric" format="int" default="3" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Maximum size of a component to be pruned.
	  </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
All the components having a size smaller or equal to the given maximum are
considered as ''small'' and stored into the file for <i>small</i>
components. The remaining components are stored into the file for <i>big</i>
components.
]]>
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


  </paramlist>


</application>
