<?xml version="1.0"?>

<application>


  <descr>
    <name>Morphological closing</name>
    <author>Qgar Project, LORIA</author>
    <copyright>2004 - Qgar Project, LORIA</copyright>
  </descr>


  <documentation>
    <doc>
      <brief>
Closing of a given binary image using mathematical morphology operations.
      </brief>
      <long>
<![CDATA[
<p>
A <b>closing</b> is a mathematical morphology operation, which is the
composition of a dilation and an erosion (8-connexity-based), using a square as
structural element. The size (i.e. width) of the structural element should be an
odd number. If it is not the case, the size is automatically rounded to the
nearest superior odd number.
</p>
<p>
The result is a binary image containing the white pixels sets of the source
image which match (are identical to) the structural element. In other words, it
does not contain any white region smaller than the structural element.
</p>
<p>
<b>Warning:</b> Let <i>s</i> be the size of the structural element.
Because of the very nature of dilation and erosion, the content of the <i>s</i>
rows and columns contiguous to the borders of the resulting image is not
relevant.
</p>
]]>
      </long>
    </doc>
  </documentation>


  <paramlist>


    <param name="source image" flag="in" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="binary" format="PBM">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file containing the source binary image.
          </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file must be one of the binary formats described
by the PBM+ specification (either raw or ASCII).
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="result image" flag="out" required="true"
	   passing-mode="out" type="binary" format="PBM"
	   default="_.closed.pbm">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file to store the closing of the source image.
          </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
	  </long>	  
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="structural element size" flag="size" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="int"
	   min="1" default="5">	   
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Size (i.e. width) of the square structural element used for the opening.
          </brief>
	  <long>
The size of the structural element must be an odd number. If the supplied value
is an even number, it is automatically rounded to the nearest superior odd
number.
	  </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


  </paramlist>


</application>
