<?xml version="1.0"?>

<application>

  <descr>
    <name>Image degradation using Kanungo's method</name>
    <author>Qgar Project, LORIA</author>
    <copyright>2004 - Qgar Project, LORIA</copyright>
  </descr>


  <documentation>
    <doc>
      <brief>
Degradation of a binary image, using Kanungo's method.
      </brief>
      <long>
<![CDATA[
<p>
Degradations introduced are similar to the noise obtained when a document is
scanned, printed or photocopied. Two kinds of noise are introduced:
 A global one (tuned by parameter <tt>-eta</tt>)
and a local one (tuned by parameters
<tt>-a</tt>, <tt>-a0</tt>, <tt>-b</tt>, and <tt>-b0</tt>).
A morphological closing (tuned by parameter <tt>-size</tt>)
may be finally applied to the degraded image.
</p>
<p>
See
<i>T. Kanungo, R.M. Haralick, H.S. Baird, W. Stuezle, and D. Madigan.
A statistical, nonparametric methodology for document degradation model
validation. IEEE Transactions on PAMI, 22(11):1209-1223, November 2000.</i>
</p>
<p>
<b>Warning:</b> The content of the rows and columns contiguous
to the borders of the given image is not degraded.
</p>
]]>
      </long>
    </doc>
  </documentation>


  <paramlist>


    <param name="source image" flag="in" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="binary" format="PBM">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file containing the binary source image.
          </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file must be one of the binary formats
described by the PBM+ specification (either raw or ASCII).
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="result image" flag="out" required="true"
	   passing-mode="out" type="binary" format="PBM"
	   default="_.kanungo.pbm" >
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Full pathname of the file to store the degraded image.
          </brief>
	  <long>
The format of the file is raw PBM.
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="alpha" flag="a" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="real"
	   default="0.5" min="0" >
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Decay speed of the noise related to black components.
          </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
The noise is introduced in a black component according to the distance
between a considered pixel of the component and the closest border
of the component. The decay speed is an exponential parameter:
The more this value is low, the more the thickness of the influence
area of the noise close to the borders is large.
In particular, a null value ensures that the noise determined by
parameter <tt>alpha0</tt> (flag <tt>a0</tt>)
is introduced in the whole area of all black components.
]]>
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="alpha0" flag="a0" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="real"
	   default="0.5" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Strength of the (white) noise related to black components.
          </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
The more this value is high, the more the noise is important.
The noise is introduced inside black components at an average
distance from the borders, controlled by parameter <tt>alpha</tt>
(flag <tt>-a</tt>).
]]>
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="beta" flag="b" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="real"
	   default="0.5" min="0" >
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Decay speed of the noise related to white components.
          </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
The noise is introduced inside white components according to the distance
between a considered pixel of the component and the closest border of the
component. The decay speed is an exponential parameter:
The more this value is low, the more the thickness of the influence area
of the noise close to the borders is large.
In particular, a null value ensures that the noise determined by parameter
<tt>beta0</tt> (flag <tt>-b0</tt>) is introduced in the whole area of all
white components.
]]>
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="beta0" flag="b0" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="real"
	   default="0.5" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Strength of the (black) noise related to white components.
          </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
The more this value is high, the more the noise is important.
The noise is introduced inside white components, at an average
distance from the borders, controlled by parameter <tt>beta</tt>
(flag <tt>-b</tt>).
]]>
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="eta" flag="eta" required="true" passing-mode="in"
           type="numeric" format="real" default="0.0" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Strength of the global noise applied to the binary image.
          </brief>
	  <long>
<![CDATA[
This parameter represents the constant probability of flipping
(from white to black or from black to white) for all pixels.
Thus, the expected value must be between <tt>0.0</tt> (no global noise)
and <tt>1.0</tt> (global noise everywhere).
]]>
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


    <param name="structural element size" flag="size" required="true"
	   passing-mode="in" type="numeric" format="int" default="1" min="0">
      <documentation>
	<doc>
	  <brief>
Size (i.e. width) of the square structural element to be used
for the final closing.
          </brief>
	  <long>
In fact, the effective size is an odd number, equal to two times
the supplied value, plus 1.
          </long>
	</doc>
      </documentation>
    </param>


  </paramlist>


</application>
